A Guide to the Anthony Family Papers, 1788-1868
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Anthony Family Papers, 1788-1868
The Library of Virginia
21546
12 leaves and 19 pages
Anthony Family
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Purchased from T. J. Bell of Bedford, Virginia, 13-14 June 1939
Biographical Information
The Anthonys were a prominent family in Bedford and Campbell Counties, Virginia. John Anthony (1746-1822) entered the Baptist ministry in 1776 and established the Otter Church, later renamed Bethlehem Church, in Bedford County, serving its congregation until his death. One son, Charles Anthony (1793-1884), became a successful farmer in Campbell County, establishing his home "Walnut Hill" on the Otter River. Both John and Charles Anthony are buried there. Another son, Abner Anthony (1790-1884), followed his father into the ministry. He served the Staunton Church and rode circuit to other churches in Bedford, Franklin, and Pittsylvania Counties. Abner Anthony established his family home, "Cedar Hill," in Bedford County. He and his wife, Almira Anthony (1820-1893), had nine children, two of whom, Charles Lewis Anthony (1837-1922) and Penn Anthony (1861-1952), continued the tradition of their father and grandfather by becoming Baptist ministers.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1788-1868, of the Anthony family of Bedford and Campbell Counties, Virginia, consisting of deeds for real property, personal property and slaves; agreements on a lease between members of the Anthony family; judicial records concerning court cases involving members of the Anthony family; plats and surveys for property, including land in Pittsylvania County, Virginia; Abner Anthony's certificate of ordination as a Baptist minister and two circular letters from Baptist ministers; and a promissory note, a receipt, a power of attorney, and a bond concerning members of the Anthony family.
Contents List
- Plat, 2 January 1788, for 630 acres belonging to William Irvine (d. 1796) of Pittsylvania County, Virginia.
- Deed, dated 15 December 1803 and recorded 19 December 1803 in Pittsylvania County, for 200 acres in Pittsylvania County from Nicholas and Elizabeth Robinson of Franklin County, Virginia, to John Anthony (1746-1822).
- Agreement, 3 January 1814, between John Anthony and Abner Anthony (1790-1884), both of Campbell County, Virginia..
- Agreement, 3 January 1814 and continuation 14 October 1817, between John Anthony and Abner Anthony (1790-1884).
- Promissory note, dated 3 February 1814 and paid March 1816, from Abner Anthony and Mark Anthony (1780-1859), both of Bedford County, Virginia, to Arthur H. Robinson of Pittsylvania County.
- Receipt, 19 June 1818, from John Seay to Abner Anthony.
- Power of attorney, 15 November 1819, from Mary C. Goolsby of Pittsylvania County to Abner Anthony of Bedford County.
- Deed dated March 1820 and recorded 21 August 1820 in Pittsylvania County, for certain personal property, from David Moore (d. 1831) of Pittsylvania County to Abner Anthony of Bedford County and Frederick Obertheir (b. ca. 1798) of Pittsylvania County.
- Deed, dated 29 December 1820 and recorded 12 March 1821 in Campbell County, for slaves, from John Anthony to Mark Anthony.
- Bond, 5 December 1821, from Benjamin Rives and George Fosdick to Nelson Davis (ca. 1769-1856), all of Pittsylvania County.
- Court order, 8 December 1823, for Mark Anthony and Daniel W. Love (b. ca. 1797) against Abner Anthony, Charles Anthony (1793-1884), and John Seay. Superior Court of Chancery, Lynchburg District.
- Certificate of ordination, 28 May 1827, of Abner Anthony as a Baptist minister.
- Decree, 3 December 1845, in the suit of English, et al vs Abner Anthony, Franklin County Court.
- abstract of proceedings, 1846-1849, in a suit of Mark Anthony in [Campbell County?] court.
- Circular letter, 16 August 1853, from the Reverend John Lamb Prichard (1812-1863) of Bedford County, President of the Baptist Strawberry Association.
- Survey, 20 October 1857, of 20 1/2 acres belonging to John Ellis (1825-1890) of Pittsylvania County.
- Deed, recorded 4 February 1868, from Abner Anthony to his wife and children (incomplete copy).
- Decree, 2 October 1868, in the suit of Matthew R. Allen (1814-1887) of Franklin County against Abner Anthony.
- Circular letter, September 1868, from the Reverend George F. Adams (1802-1877) of Hampton, Virginia.
- Abner Anthony's answer to a complaint filed against him by Mark Anthony, Superior Court of Chancery, Lynchburg District.
- Plat of the proposed town of Monroeton to be located in Pittsylvania County.